MICHAEL MELLO PAPERS (APAP287) 1800-2008
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Publications, 1979-2006; 6; 4.4
  - " Who is the Real 'Outlaw' Here: Joseph Spaziano, Florida Governor Lawton Chilos, or the State and Federal Judiciaries?"- Drafts ( 2 of 3), 1995 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - " Who is the Real 'Outlaw' Here: Joseph Spaziano, Florida Governor Lawton Chiles, of the State and the Federal Judiciaries?"- Drafts (3 of 3)-Drafts, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft ( 1 of 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft ( 1 of 2), Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Wrong Man: A Trust Story of Innocence on Death Row - Poster, 2001 (Map-tube 1)
- Research Files, 1800-2004; 7; 14
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains files associated with Michael Mellos research for his publications, his legal work, or his classroom work. The research files cover a range of topics including juveniles on death row, jury override, and the adequate representation for indigent inmates and represent legal materials, academic articles, newspaper articles, and correspondence regarding various cases and legal issues.
  - The Bartkos Exception to the Dual Sovereighty Doctorine, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bas v. Tingy, 1800 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Beasley v. Holland, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Berea College v. Kentucky, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bill Tracking Reports for Various U.S. States Concerning Juveniles and the Death Penalty, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Blake v. Zant, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Blystone v. Pennsylvania, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bounds v. Smith, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bowden v. Francis, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Boyde v. California, 1988; 1990 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Brady v. Maryland, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Joseph Green Brown, 1985; 1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Brown v. Dugger, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Brown v. Kemp- USDC, GA- Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Bryan v. Koch, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - In the Shadow of the Capital: Childhood hunger in Washington, D.C., Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Burch v. Florida, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Bush v. Texas, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Butler v. Aiken, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Cabana v. Bullock, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Calder v. Bull, 1798 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Bobby Caldwell, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - California Appellate Project- Program Description, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, ( 1 of 2), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, ( 2 of 2), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP ( 1 of 2), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP ( 2 of 2), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP ( 1 of 2), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP ( 2 of 2), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Cannon v. Unversity of Chicago, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Capital Collateral Representative-Presentation to Senate Appropriations Subcommittee, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Capital Defender Office- Beginnings and Description, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Capital Defender Office- Creation, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Capital Defender Office- Funding, 1986; 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Capital Defender Office- Governor's Budget Proposal, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Capital Defender Office- Potential Problems, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Capital Losses: The Price of the Death Penalty for New York State- Public Defense Backup Center, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Capital Punishment as a System" by Jack Greenberg, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Capital Punishment for Minors: An Eighth Amendment Analysis" by Helene B. Greenwald, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Capital Sentencing in Kentucky: An Examination of Juvenile Case Characteristics" by Vito and Keil, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Card v. Dugger, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Carey v. Garrison, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Carnes Disqualification Research, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cases of Kids on Death Row, 1968; 1979; 1982-1984; 1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cave v. State, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Certiorari Improvidently Granted, 1916; 1924; 1944; 1955; 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Certiorari Improvidently Granted, 1967-1972; 1977; 1981 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - The Challenge of Crime in a Free Society: A Report by the President's Commission on Law Enforcement and Administration of Justice, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Chaney v. Lewis, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - The Changing Legal World of Adolescence by Franklin E. Zimring, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Changing Youth in a Changing Society by Michael Rutter ( 1 of 2), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Changing Youth in a Changing Society by Michael Rutter ( 2 of 2), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Chief Judge Oakes, US CA 2nd Circuit, Hearings on S.635, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The Child and Death edited by Olle Jane V. Sahlec, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Childhood and Society by Erik H Erikson- Chapter 7, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "Children and Death: From the School Setting Viewpoint" by Delphie J. Fredlond, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Children's Conception of Death by Richard Lonetto, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - "Children's Liberation and the New EgalHananism: Some Reservations About Abandoning Youth to their 'Rights' " by Bruce C. Hafen, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "Civic Virtue and the Feminine Voice in Constitutional Adjudication" by Suzanna Sherry, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - "Civil Disobedience and Operation Rescue: A Historical and Theoretical Analysis" by John W. Whitehead, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - "Civil Disobedience and the Lawyer's Obligation to the Law" by Judith A. McMorrow, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "Civil Law Regulation of Reproductive Technologies: New Laws for the New Biology?" by Joan Bercovitch, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Civil Rights Act of 1984- H.R. 5490 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Civil Rights Act of 1984- S.2568- Part 1 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Civil Rights Act of 1984- S.2568- Part 2 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Civil Rights Restoration Act of 1985, 1986 (Oversized 1, Item 3)
  - Clisby v. Jones, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Coker v. Georgia, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Coleman v. Saffle, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Coleman v. Thompson, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - "Collateral Post Conviction Remedies in Florida" by Gene D. Brown, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Collier v. State, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - "Combatting Racial Violence: A Legislative Propasal"- Havard Law Review, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Commentary on Death Penalty in NY, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - "Comments on Women's Law in Scandinavia" by Agnete Weis Bentzon, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - "Competence for Execution Role can Exact Personal Price" by Kathleen Fisher, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - "The Concept of the Doctrine of the Court in Constitutional Law" by Earl M. Maltz, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Confronting Youth Crime- Report of the Twentieth Century Fund Task on Sentencing Policy Toward Young Offenders: Background Paper by Franklin E. Zimring, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - "The Construction of the United States: Contemporary Ratification" by William J. Brennon, JR., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - "Constitutional Adjudication and the Death Penalty: A View From the Court" by William J. Brennan, JR.,-1986 Oliver Wendell Holmes, Jr. lecture (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - "Constitutional Jurisprudence of History and Natural Law: Complimentary of Rival Modes of Discourse?" by C.M.A McCauliff, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - "Constitutional Law- Eighth Amendment-cruel and unusual Punishment-The Prejudice effect of the Prosecutor's Comment on the Capital Sentencing Jury"- Mississipi Law Journal, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Constitutional Law- Recent Developments, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Constitutionality of the Death Penalty in New York, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - "Contingency and Community in Normative Practice" by Steven L. Winter, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "Conventional Morality and Judical Standards" by Wojciesh Sadurks, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Cooper v. Dugger, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Counsel for Indigent Habeas Petitioner, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Crime and Human Nature by Wilson and Herrnstein- Excerpt, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Crime in the US- FBI Uniform Crime Reports, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Criminal Justice Act, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Criminal Justice Act, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Criminal Justice Act, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Criminal Justice Act, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Criminal Procedure- An Indigent's Constitutional Right to a State- Paid Expert", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cumming v. Richmond County Board of Education, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Curfew Statutes, 1977; 1984; 1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Darkness on the Edge of Town: The Contributions of John Hart Ely to Constitutional Theory" by Mark Tushnet, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Deadly Mistakes: Harmless Error in Capital Sentencing" by James C. Scoville, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Death- Innonece and the Law of Habeus Corpus" by Stephen P. Garvey, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Death Penalty" by Criag Barnard, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "The Death Penalty and Juveniles" by Charles Z. Smith, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Death Penalty Cases", 1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Death Penalty in America (Third Edition)- Hugo Adam Bedau- Excerpts, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - The Death Penalty in 2003: Year End Report- Death Penalty Information Center (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Death Row Representation, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Death Sentences Imposed, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - "The Decency of Capital Punishment For Minors: Contemporary Standards and the Dignity of Juveniles" by Lawrence A. Vanore, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - "Deciding Who Dies" by Stephen Gillers, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "Defining Due Process of Law: The Case of Mr. Justice Hugo L. Black" by Roger W. Haigh, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1948; 1964; 1966; 1971; 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "Defunding Death"-Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "Defunding Death"-Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Dual Prosecution and Successive Federal Prosecution Policies, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Determining Eligibility For Appointed Counsel in New York State- Public Defense Backy Center, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Devier v. Kemp, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - The Dilemmas of Liberal Constitutionalism by Mark Tushnet, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Disorder in the Court: The Death Penalty and the Constitution" by Robert A. Burt, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "The Dissenting Opinion- Its Use and Abuse" by Evan A. Evans, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Dissenting Opinion- Cornell Law Quarterly", 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "The Dissenting Opinions of Mr. Justice Daniel" by H.B. Brown, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "The Dissenting Opinions of Mr. Justice Harlan" by H.B. Brown, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Dissent and Stare Decisis in the Supreme Court", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "The Dissent that Telegraphs", Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Division of Opinion in the Supreme Court: A History of Judicial Disintegration" by Karl M. ZoBelt, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Divorce Mediation: A Feminist Perpective" by Martha Shaffer, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Do we have an Unwritten Constitution?" by Thomas C. Grey, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Do We Need a Philosophy of Law?" by Roscoe Pound, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "The Doctrine of Stare Decisis" by E.M. Wise, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Doe v. LaBrosse, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Douglas- Consistent Dissents, Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Douglas v. Florida, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Draft Rules for Appointments of Counsel in Federal Death Penalty Cases, Eastern and Southern Districts of New York, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Drinking Age Report ( 1 of 2), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Drinking Age Report ( 2 of 2), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Drug Laws, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Eddings v. Oklahoma, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Editorials and Letters to the Editor Regarding the Juvenile Death Penalty, 1987-1988; Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Elledge v. Dugger, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "The Emergence of Feminist Jurisprudence: An Essay" by Ann C. Scales, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "Equality and Feminist Legal Theory" by Christine A. Littlebon, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Evidence Outside Record Impermissible, 1851; 1966; 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "Excluded Voices: New Voices in the Legal Profession Making New Voices in the Law" by Carrie Menkel-Meadow, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Execution of Mentally Retarded Persons Under S.66001 A. 8963, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Execution in the United States in 2004, 2004 January (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - "Execution of Whites for Crimes Against Blacks: Execptions to the Rule?" by Michael Radelet, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Executions Scheduled for 2004 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Exonerations by State 1973- Present, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - "Experimental Analysis: A Contribution to Feminist Research" by Sholamit Reinharz, ca. 1983 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - "Expert Services in the Defense of Criminal Case: The Constitutional and Stationary Rights of Indigents" by John F. Decker, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - "An Extension of the Rights of Access: The Pro Se Litigant's Right to the Notification of the Requirements of the Summary Judgement Rule" by Joseph M. McLaughlin, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Facing the Death Penalty Edited by Michael Radelet-Giarratano Chapter, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Barry Lee Fairchild, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Felker v. Turpin, 1996 May 17 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Federal Cases of Interest, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - The Federal Penalty Act of 1989 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Federal Death Penalty Cases: Recommendations Concerning the Cost and Quality of Defense Representation- Subcommitee on Federal Death Penalty Cases, Committee on Defender Services, Judicial Conference of the United States, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Federal Expenditures by State for FYI, 1992; 1993 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Federal Habeas Corpus Practice and Procedure: 1991 Cumulative Supplement by Liebman and Goldstein, ca. 1991 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Federal Hitchcock Cases, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - "Feminism and Legal Method: The Difference it Makes" by Mary Jane Mossman, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - "Feminism, Epistemology and the Rhetoric of Law: Reading Bowen v. Gillard" by A.W. Phinney III, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - "Feminist Disclosure, Moral Values, and the Law- A Conservation" by Marcos et. al- The 1984 James McCormick Mitchell Leture, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Feminist Jurisprudence Articles, Undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - "Feminist Jurisprudence: Illusion or Reality?" by Margaret Thornton, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Fenemore v. US, 1797 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Final Report of the National Commission on Reform of Federal Criminal Laws- Chapter 36, Sentencing of Death of Life Imprisonment, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - "Financing the Right to Counsel in Capital Cases" by Michael Millman, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - "The First Decade of the Supreme Court of the United States" by Charles Warren, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Fletcher v. Peck, 1810 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Florida Cases Finding Hitchcock error harmless, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Florida Supreme Court Capital Case Decisions, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Florida Supreme Court Capital Case Decisions, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Florida v. Pitts, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - "For Jurisprudential Sociology" by Philippe Nonet, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - "For What It's Worth" by Steven L. Winter, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - James A. Ford, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - "The Forked Path of Dissent" by Maurice Kelman, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - "Form and Function in the Administration of Justice: The Bill of Rights and Federal Habeas Corpus" by Larry Yackle, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - "Four theories of Precedent and its Role in Judicial Decisions" by James G. Gisenhower III, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Francis v. Spraggins, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Franklin v. Lynavgh, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Frazier v. Garrison IS.D., 1993 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - "Freedom and Constraint in Adjudication" by Duncan Kennedy, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - "The Function of Comparative Law" by Pierre Lepaulle, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - The Gallup Report- "The Death Penalty", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - "Gender and Jurisprudence: An Agenda for Research" by Deborah L. Rhode, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Georgia Statute- Juveniles, 1986; Undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Georgia Supreme Court- Juveniles, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Glock v. Singletary, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Godfrey v. Georgia, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Goodie v. Wainwright, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Gorham v. Florida, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gosch v. Collins, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Goss v. Lopez, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gary Graham, 1988; 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Green v. Zant, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Grossman v. Florida, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Grove City, 1980-1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Grove City, 1980-1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Grove City, 1980-1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Grove City Legislation, 1984-1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Grove City Legislation, 1984-1988; Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Guaranteed Student Loan and Civil Rights Enforcement, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Guardians Assn. v. Civil Serv. Comm'n NYC, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Habeus Corpus as a Safety Value for Intelligence" by Bruce Ledewitz, Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - HAC- Model Agrument for FSC briefs on the direct appeal, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Hall v. DeCuir, 1877 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Handbook of Existing Rules Pertaining to Human Rights in the Inter-American System, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Hayburn, 1792 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Hearst v. US, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Highway Safety Legislation, 1986; Undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Hill v. Florida, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - History of the Death Penalty in New York, 1991; 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Hitchcock Error Cases, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Hitchcock Error Cases, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Hitchcock Error Cases, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Hitchcock Error Cases, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - "Holmes and Brandeis: Libertarian and Republic Justifications for Free Speech" by Pnina Lahav, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - "Holmes: His First Amendment Theory and His Pragmatist Bent" by Edward J. Bloustein, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Holsworth v. Florida, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Hooks v. Wainwright, 1982; 1985 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - House of Representatives Congressional Record, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - House v. Balkcom, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - "How goes the Supreme Court?" by William J. Brennan, JR., 1985 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - "How to do What We Want to do: Thoughts about Feminist Methodology" by Renate Duelli Klein, ca. 1983 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - "The Human Dimension in Appellate Judging: A Brief Reflection on a Timeless Concern" by Judith S. Kaye, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - "Humane Law and Humanistic Justice" by Edward de Grazia, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - "Humanizing the Criminal Process: Some Decisions of Mr. Justice Marshall" by David L. Bazelon, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - "The Idea of a Commutarian Morality" by Philip Selznick, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - "Imposing the Death Penalty on Juvenile Murders: A Constitutional Assessment" by Dome and Gewerth, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Imposition of Death Sentences For Juvenile Offenses, January 1, 1982, Through June 24, 1988 by Victor L. Streib (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "In Defense of Dissents" by William J.Brennan, JR., 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - In Forma Libris, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "In Memoriam- Law Day Address at the University of Texas: The Enlightened Jurisprudence of Justice Thurgood Marshall" by William Wayne Justice, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "In Search of a Feminist Jurisprudence" by Christine A. Littleton, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "In Your Court: State Judicial Federalism in Capital Cases" by Wright & Miller, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Index of Hitchcock Cases, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "The Indigent Accused, The Psychiatrist, and the Insanity Defense" by Goldstein and Fine, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "The Indigent Criminal Defendant and Defense Services: A Search for Constitutional Standards" by Margolin and Wagner, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "The Indigent's Right to an Adequate Defense: Expert and Investigational Assistancein Criminal Proceedings", 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Ingraham v. Wright, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "Innocence and Affirmative Action" by Thomas Ross, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Innocence and the Death Penalty: Assesssing the Danger of Mistaken Executions- Staff Report by the Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights, Committee on the Judiciary, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - The Insanity Defense by Abraham Goldstein- Excerpt, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Inter-American Commission on Human Rights- Resolution N 3/87, Case N9647, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - International Human Rights Treaties- Hearings Before the Committee on Foreign Relations- United States Senate, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Interpretation of Judiciary Law 35-B, S125.27, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Invisibility of Women in Labor Law: Gender- Neutrality in Model-Building" by Joanne Conoghan, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "It is Mitigation or Aggravation? Troublesome Areas of Defense Evidence in Capital Sentencing" by Deana Dorman Logan, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Sonia Jacobs, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "John Marshall Harlan", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "John Marshall Harlan: A Justice Neglected" by Henry J. Abraham, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Marvin Edwin Johnson, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Terrell M. Johnson, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Johnson v. Mississippi, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - The Journal of the National Prison Project, Summer, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - "The Judgement Intuitive: the Function of the 'Hunch' in Judicial Decisions" by Joseph C. Hutcheson, Jr., 1982 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "Judicial Obligation, Precedent and the Common Land" by Stephen R. Perry, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - "Judicial Review and the Rights and Laws of Nature" by Walter Berns, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - "Judicial Review" by Mark v. Tushnet, Undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Judi- Crim meeting, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 32)